## José Iván Flores Hernández

ivanfshz.github.io | (412) 519-4815 | ivanfshz@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with over 9 years of experience implementing the full software development lifecycle of web-based applications. Focused on best practices, high standards, and user-oriented processes with a high knowledge of various results-oriented & cost effective methodologies and strategies.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# 2018-Present | Software Developer Sr at Sngular | Pittsburgh

- → Define strategies to implement solutions based on microservices architecture with Restful API implemented with Java 8 and Spring Boot
- → Implement more recent technologies to improve performance such as Kafka, MongoDB, Docker and OpenShift
- → Define plans and strategies to promote software on time according to deadlines based on Agile frameworks
- → Ensure the quality of code by implementing Unit and Integration tests with Spock
- → Help to define workflows and reference models to promote deliveries involving best practices and quality by implementing technical solutions focused on customer experience

### 2017-2018 | Software Developer Sr at Globant MX | México City

- → Worked closely with DevOps experts to migrate and set up multi-platform components to CaaS cloud services with Docker, Kubernetes and Azure
- → Defined workflows guidelines for CI & CD that involved integrations with Maven, GitHub, Docker Registry, Jenkins & VSTS and JUnit Testing stages.
- → Migrated legacy Java applications from version 1.6 to 1.8 version while ensuring a scalability and enhancements of services
- → Identified and solved technical debt by measuring the quality of code, tests focus on stability and quality by Implementing Spock and SonarQube and 2to2 reviews

## 2014-2017 | Software Developer Sr at HSBC México | México City

- → Developed web services and microservices based on services oriented architecture with java technology and different frameworks such as spring, spring-security, spring-rest, spring integrations, jax-ws, oracle and AngularJS
- → Improve the performance Implemented technologies to transfer and consume information by different managed file transfer protocols such as IBM Websphere MQ and Apache Camel.

# José Iván Flores Hernández

ivanfshz.github.io | (412) 519-4815 | ivanfshz@gmail.com

- → Worked effectively with teams involved on agile framework, continuous integration and DevOps to optimize the value of the deliveries and reduced the costs of the implementations
- → Reduced 70% of the license expenses by migrating the platform to open source
- → First LATAM team to automated deliveries to promote faster and safer software to production every 2 weeks involving best practices and quality standards
- → Participated as a Scrum Master on different teams and implementing the best practices of the framework in order to reduce the time on deliveries

### **EDUCATION**

2008-2012 | B.E. Computer Engineering | Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

2020 | Oracle Java SE 8 Programmer l (*In progress*)

2016 | Professional Scrum Master l by <u>scrum.org</u>

2016 | Postgraduate diploma in Java Oriented to Web Applications Development | UNAM

#### **SKILLS**

Methodologies	Technologies	
Agile DevOps Microservices OOP Prototype development Test Driven Development (TDD) Behavior-driven development (BDD) Waterfall development P2P Review Knowledge Management	Java Spring Boot Spock Git MongoDB Oracle Angular Docker Artifactory OpenShift Kafka Maven	JUnit Jira SonarQube Angular Azure OpenShift Artifactory Jenkins VSTS Linux Gradle CSS

### **LANGUAGES**

**English** Full Professional Proficiency

★★★★

**Spanish** Native Proficiency

\*\*\*\*